Jackson Meier

Phone: (513) 265-4090 | Email: jackson.meier423@gmail.com | Possess Active TS/SCI Clearance

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/jackson-meier

GitHub Profile: https://github.com/meierj423

Portfolio: https://meierj423.github.io/portfolio-page-v2/

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Developer with experience in designing, developing, and maintaining web applications. Recognized as an enthusiastic team-player with excellent communication and interpersonal skills. Able to learn new concepts quickly due to strong problem-solving skills and analytical mindset.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars.js
- Platforms and Frameworks: GitHub, Heroku, Bootstrap, Express.js, Node.js
- <u>Libraries:</u> jQuery, React.js, Sequelize.js
- <u>Databases:</u> MongoDB, MySQL

PROJECTS

Devour a Burger | GitHub: https://github.com/meierj423/burger **Deployed Project:** https://afternoon-cliffs-58576.herokuapp.com/

- An application for keeping track of burgers that have either been devoured or soon to be devoured
- Role: Sole Developer
- Languages/Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, Handlebars.js, Node.js, Express.js

Day Planner | GitHub: https://github.com/meierj423/day-planner
Deployed Project: https://meierj423.github.io/day-planner/

- An application for keeping track of daily tasks
- Role: Sole Developer
- Languages/Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Sorting Hat Quiz | GitHub: https://github.com/tlam1288/Sorting-Hat-Quiz Deployed Project: https://tlam1288.github.io/Sorting-Hat-Quiz/

- An application for seeing which Hogwarts House a user belongs to
- **Role**: Front-end developer in a group of three other developers
- Languages/Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Foundation, jQuery, Ajax

EXPERIENCE

Intelligence Officer | U.S. Navy | November 2018 - June 2020 | Coronado, CA

- Responsible for developing comprehensive threat assessments on adversary's strengths, weaknesses, capabilities, and intentions
- Conducted briefs to both peers and senior ranking officials in order to provide understanding on multiple complex issues

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Submarine Officer | U.S. Navy | August 2017- November 2018 | Charleston, SC

Sailing Instructor | U.S. Navy | May 2017 - August 2017 | Annapolis, MD

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development UC San Diego Extension | June 2020 - September 2020

Bachelor of Science (with Merit)
Mathematics | United States Naval Academy | Annapolis, MD | June 2013 - May 2017